these remains dating from the iron age,
这尸体来自铁器时代
were found at the bottom of shaft three at the site.
是在三号支柱底下找到的
There were five sets of human remains found.
总共有5具尸体
This is the only one found whole.
这是唯一一具完整的
He's in good shape.
他看起来保存得很好
1,500 years old: He shouldn't look this good.
1500年了, 不应该看起来这么完好
Which is why we're here.
这就是为什么要我们帮忙
We're either going to authenticate the finest set
要么我们去鉴定迄今为止找到的
of human remains from the iron age ever found,
保存最好的铁器时代遗骸
or dash the hopes of a thousand scholars.
或者让学者们对此失望
Let me know how it turns out.
有结果就告诉我
But,dr. Goodman,
但是, Goodman博士, 这案子很有价值
this is extremely prestigious. Aren't you going to be a part of the team?
您不参加吗?
- I have an institution to run. - Didn't you used to be an archaeologist?
- 我还得管这个机构呢 - 你以前是不是一个考古学家?
Yes,mr. Addy.
是的, Addy先生
Thanks for reminding me.
谢谢你提醒我
X-rays. Pictures.
拍X光，照片
We're gonna do this without touching the actual skeleton as much as possible.
我们要尽可能的不去碰到尸骨
Kid gloves?
要戴套么?
Latex should be all right.
用乳液就可以了
Zack,were you being metaphoric?
Zack你在打什么暗喻吗?
I decided to give it a shot.
我只是决定试试
Which is also metaphoric.
也是个比喻
I need a receptionist.
我需要一个接待员
I can't have just anybody waltzing in here.
我可不想别人随便进来
Take a look at this.
看看这个
A bunch of red circles?
一组红色圆圈?
Each circle shows where a body part was found.
每个圆圈标示了遗骸的发现地点
- What is this,an airport? - Los angeles international.
- 这是什么地方，飞机场? - 洛杉矶国际机场
Local pathologist says the remains are in pretty bad shape.
当地法医说尸体腐烂得相当糟糕
So he punted to the fbi.
所以他们把球踢给FBI
Airports,they fall under federal jurisdiction.
机场说这归联邦管辖
Excellent use of the word "punt."
"踢球"这个说法用得真棒
I can't go to los angeles, I have an iron age warrior to authenticate.
我不能去洛杉矶 我有一具铁器时代的武士尸体要鉴定
Iron age warrior? Okay,when was the iron age?
铁器时代的武士? 那是什么时候?
1,500 years ago.
1500年前
No. Fresh body bits,just a little bit more urgent.
不，新的尸体比较要紧
You do realize there are lot more fresh bodies
你了不了解新的尸体
than there are perfect specimens from the iron age?
比铁器时代的样品要多得多?
And when you say things like that, it's just to bug me,right?
你每次这么说只是想损我, 对吧
Do we have to go through this every time?
每次我们都必须这么做吗?
Exactly.
当然
Booth can't just walk in and say,
Booth不能随便走进来然后说
- "pack your bags,we're going to L.A." - Oh,yeah,yeah. The whole ice age warrior thing.
- "打包 我们去L.A." - 哦，好吧好吧，又是冰川时代的战士
- Iron age. - Iron age.
- 铁器时代 - 铁器时代
And that's not the only thing.
并不仅仅因为这件事
Homeland security has just asked dr. Brennan to identify three bodies found in...
国家安全局刚刚要求Brennan博士 去鉴定三具尸体，是在...
- I'm not allowed to say. - The point is,agent booth,
- 我不能说 - Booth探员, 问题的关键在于
dr. Brennan is in great demand on several very pressing cases
Brennan博士实在是事务繁忙
and she's needed here at the museum.
她也需要留在博物馆
Why shld I send her to california?
我为什么要把她送去加州?
Sexy case in hollywood?
好莱坞的性犯罪案子?
How much more good press could the jeffersonian get?
这将给Jeffersonian带来多大的影响力?
But,dr. Goodman?
可是, Goodman博士
You said the iron age warrior was of the highest priority.
你说这铁器时代的武士是最重要的
I can step in on that case.
我可以接那个案子
You pack your bags.
你收拾好你的行李
This car doesn't feel very fbi-ey.
这部车没有一点FBI的样子
Hey,bones,this is a 1966 mustang. It's a classic.
嗨, Bones, 这是66年的野马, 是最棒的
I mean,what goes better than that with the fbi?
我是说还有什么更适合FBI的探员?
How come on the rental agreement under "model" you made the guy write "sedan"?
那你为什么在租赁合同的类型一栏 写箱式货车?
Come on. We're california.
得了, 我们这是在加洲
Look,palm trees.
看, 棕榈树
Yeah,I'd like to drive sometime.
对了，我想偶尔开开车
Look,our contact out here is special agent tricia finn.
我们在本地的联系人是Tricia Finn特工
I'm an excellent driver.
我车开得很棒
- Okay,rainman. - I don't know what that means.
- 得了, "雨人" - 说什么呢
Well,I'm always going to drive. You know that,right?
好了, 一向是我开车, 你知道的, 对吧?
Me behind the wheel,and you over there on the grandma side.
我开车的时候, 你还在祖母身边撒娇呢
I'm not above telling deputy director cullen what kind of car you rented.
那么我就告诉你上司Cullen你租了什么车
Do you want us to do something, or just stand here and watch?
你需要我们做点什么 还是仅仅站在这儿旁观?
I'm getting a feel for the fellow.
我正在寻找接下来的灵感
- A feel? - Well,there's no bugs on him,
- 灵感? - 恩, 在他的身上并没有虫子
haven't been for over a thousand years.
不像是过了上千年的样子
There may be spores and pollens,correct?
这儿也许有孢子或是花粉, 对吗?
Probably not.
恐怕没有
Dozens of species of pollens have been discovered from the cretaceous era--
出土的白垩纪的样本也有许多的花粉了
how long ago was that?
那是多久以前了?
65 million years.
6500万年
That was a pretty good comeback.
很好的回答
When authenticating a find like this, we have to be at the top of our game.
每次鉴定这种出土物, 我们必须掌控一切
Yeah,well,we all know that you're gonna say, "I am unable to authenticate with confidence."
行了, 我们都知道你要说 "我不能仅凭信心来做判定"
- Why would he do that? - When you declare something authentic,
- 何出此言？ - 当你想证明某事的时候
you run the risk of being proven wrong.
你会冒着被证实是错误的危险
That doesn't happen if you equivocate.
当然如果你说话模棱两可就不会了
As head of the jeffersonian,
作为Jeffersonian的领导
dr. Goodman will place the reputation of the institution over everything else.
Goodman博士会把机构的名声看得比什么都重
I'm an archaeologist.
我是一名考古学家
My findings will be congruent with the facts.
我的结论将会基于事实
All due respect,
恕我直言
you used to be an archaeologist.
您仅仅曾经是一名考古学者
I... have no idea what's going on between you two right now.
我不知道你们之间刚才到底是怎么了
Agent finn,why was the body removed from the crime scene?
Finn探员, 为什么尸体被从罪案现场移开?
Call me tricia, dr. Brennan.
叫我Tricia, Brennan博士
The body was removed because parts were visible to arriving flights.
尸体被移开 是因为在航班到来时会被看到
Here's a map of the crime scene with a legend.
这是一张罪案现场的示意地图
Now,there's a marked cone at the location of each body part,
在发现每一个尸体的地方都作了标记
and each photograph corresponds to a cone.
每个记号都有一张现场照片对应
That's how they did it in your book.
这就是他们在你书上做的
She got that from me.
是我教她的
This is not a dismemberment.
这不是人为肢解的
Are you sure,bones? I mean,this is los angeles,you know? They're showy.
你确定吗, Bones? 我是说,这是在洛杉矶 知道吗? 他们疯狂得很
Is it possible that the body parts were ground up in a landing gear
有没有可能性 是被飞机起落架齿轮绞碎的?
and then dumped when the airplane landed?
然后在飞机着陆时落在了这里
The dispersal rate is wrong.
分布不对
It looks to me like the body was pulled apart by... a pack of dogs.
在我看来尸体是被一群狗撕碎的
- More likely,coyotes. - Coyotes at the airport?
- 更像是土狼 - 机场有土狼吗?
- We've got coyotes everywhere. - Did you know that?
- 到处都有 - 你知道吗?
No,I thought coyotes were,you know,a cowboy thing.
不，我以为，土狼是牛仔那边的东西
I'd like to see the remains now.
我想马上看看尸体
I need all the dirt,silt,bits and pieces collected with the body parts,
我需要和尸块一起收集来的所有的泥土 泥沙，还有碎片及其他东西
sent back to the jeffersonian immediately.
马上送回Jeffersonian
You know what I like? When there's no flesh on the bones.
你知道我喜欢什么吗? 没有肉的骨头
Just a personal preference.
仅仅是个人喜好
There's not much left,anyway.
但是这里的确没有多少肉
You know,dr. Brennan,
你知道的, Brennan 博士
as a screenplay writer myself,
作为一个电影编剧
I'd be happy to help you in any way I can with regard to your movie.
如果我能为你的电影写剧本我会很高兴的
Excuse me?
什么?
Someone told me they're thinking of making your book into a movie.
有人告诉我他们在考虑把你的书拍成电影
Say something,bones.
是这样吗，Bones
Well,all I know is i'm supposed to meet some big movie producer while I'm here--
我知道的只是当我在这时 我应该和一些大牌制作人见面
if I have time, which I probably won'T.
如果我有时间的话, 但恐怕是不可能的
Does the pathologist need any further access to the remaining soft tissue?
法医需要更多软组织来分析吗?
No. He got everything out of it he could.
不需要，他拿了他能拿的所有东西
So my own screenplay is about this fbi agent
我的剧本是关于这个FBI探员
who finds herself on the trail of a former boyfriend,and...
发现自己被以前的男友跟踪, 然后...
oh... um...
噢...噢...
god.
天哪
It's okay if you have to leave.
你可以回避一下
This is not good.
太糟糕了
Yeah,thanks for that insight.
对，你总算明白点
No.
不
I mean the architecture of the skull has been radically altered.
我是说这个头骨的根本结构被改变了
You mean rotting and being eaten by coyotes,
你是说腐烂了还有被土狼吃了
and having the face ripped off by you?
然后又被你把脸皮撕掉?
No,by surgery.
不, 是动过手术
Lots of surgery.
很多次手术
I'm not sure I'll be able to tell who this was.
我不确定我还能不能分辨出这是谁
-------------------------- www.ydy.com/bbs Proudly Presents --------------------------
-=伊甸园美剧 http://sfile.ydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
Sync: YTET-Starry -==www.ydy.com/bbs==-
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: Marcella  Macready 校对: Sybil 时间轴: YYET-Starry
bones Season 1 Episode 10
识骨追踪 第一季第十集
are you getting the feed,zack?
你拿到材料了吗，Zack?
Yes,dr. Brennan,I'm looking at the x-rays you beamed me.
是的, Brennan 博士 我正在看你给我的X光片
I'm going to have the bones cleaned,
我需要把这些骨头清理干净
but there's still vestiges of flesh.
但这里还有一些残存的肉
Hodgins got the clothing remnants and silt this morning.
Hodgins今天早上提取了织物纤维和残渣
Are you there,ange?
你在吗, Ange?
Is it sunny,sweetie?
阳光明媚吧, 亲爱的?
- Tell me it's sunny. - It's sunny.
- 肯定阳光明媚 - 的确如此
I sent you the entire skull.
我把整个头骨交给你了
- You want a reconstruction? - If you can.
- 你需要做重建? - 如果你可以的话
If I can? Have I ever failed you?
我可以的话? 我什么时候让你失望过?
This one's different; you'll see what I mean when you get it.
这次不一样 你拿到后就会知道我的意思
Zack?
- Here,dr. Brennan. - I make this a young woman.
- 在这儿, Brennan 博士 - 我分析这是一个年轻女子
Early 20s from the look of the x-rays.
从X光片上看应该20多岁
Cause of death?
死因?
I see evidence of stabbing.
我发现了刺伤的痕迹
One hit to the sternum,two to the costal cartilages.
一处在胸骨,另两处在肋软骨
Estimated time of death?
估计死亡时间?
Degradation of remains suggests
尸体腐烂程度显示
the body was left out in the open between a week and ten days.
尸体暴露在空气中大约一周到十天时间
And the marks on the bones suggest carnivorous feeding beyond insects, birds and rodents.
骨骼上的痕迹显示有肉食动物撕咬过
Coyotes.
土狼
- They have coyotes? - Yes.
- 那里有土狼? - 对
That would explain the dispersal of remains.
那就可以解释尸块散落得到处都是
A pack of coyotes finds the body, pulls it apart,
一群土狼发现了尸体, 把它撕碎
and spreads out to eat in solitude.
然后再各自享用
The teeth are veneered.
牙齿被镶过
The jaw has been broken and reset. Same with the right leg.
下巴脱臼过然后被复位, 右脚也是
Have you seen any movie stars yet?
你见到什么明星没有?
No,why?
没有, 怎么了?
Apparently,it's a contest when you go to L.A.,
去洛杉矶大家就会开始比较
In which the winner is the person who sees the most celebrities.
尤其是在冬天 这个最可能看到名人的时候
You have a whole skull,right?
你有一个完整的头骨, 是吗?
Yes.
当然
So,why is this going to be so difficult?
那么, 怎么还会那么困难呢?
You'll see.
你会知道的
Ange,on the iron age project,goodman does this thing. Hodgins isn't going to like it.
Ange，在铁器时代的案子里 Goodman做了一些让Hodgins看不惯的事
- What thing? - He theorizes,in a way.
- 什么事? - 在某种程度上, 他太理论化了
It sounds like he's making stuff up.
听起来他在纸上谈兵
It's hard to explain,but it's going to irritate hodgins.
很难说清, 不过这让Hodgins不太爽
Honey,you're in california.
亲爱的, 你现在在加州
Forge te iron age.
忘掉铁器时代的事吧
Say these words: "Sky bar."
去一趟"天空酒吧"
Go there tonight. Tell me everything.
今晚去吧, 然后回来给我讲
Dr. Brennan,one of these x-rays shows
Brennan博士, 有张X光片显示
two dark clumps near the pelvis.
在骨盆旁边有两处阴影
Behind what's left of the spleen?
是脾脏后面?
I've got a list of missing persons: Women in their early 20s.
我得到了一份失踪人员名单 20多岁的女子
Oh,do I really have to be here for this part?
噢, 我必须呆在这里看吗?
You think she swallowed that?
你认为那个是她吞下的?
Could be because she was a drug mule.
也许她用身体运毒
It's an implant.
这是块硅胶
Breast implant.
隆胸用的
Those come with serial numbers?
这应该有序列号
We should be able to identify our victim in a couple of hours.
我们应该在几个小时内 就可以确定受害者的身份了
Unlike other burials of the time
与同时期的其它墓葬不同
in which the remains were found in a semi-fetal position,
一般尸体是以一种半成型的婴儿姿势被埋
this fellow was found on his back,arms at his sides,
这尸体是躺着的，手放两边
with a piece of decorated antler on his chest.
胸前有一只作装饰的鹿角
Do you actually need me here?
您真需要我在这儿吗?
The antler honors him as a hunter,
鹿角象征着猎人的荣誉
although his weapons tell us he was a warrior.
尽管他的兵器告诉我们他是一个战士
He was in his mid-30s when he died.
他死的时候在35岁左右
He was 1.88 meters tall.
1.88米高
You know,there's all the detritus from brennan's hollywood crime to sift through.
你知道的, Brennnan在好莱坞的罪案 还有很多琐碎的事要分析
6'1"?
6英尺1英寸?
A big man for his time.
在那个时代可算得上大块头了
Feared by his foes, respected by his neighbors.
令敌人胆寒, 受国人崇敬的英雄
They encourage that much conjecture in archaeology?
推崇在考古中使用那么多的假设?
His bones bear the marks of battle.
他的骨骼承载了战场的烙印
His weapons are of good quality, well-used.
他的武器也是锋利无比
He was old for a warrior. Yet,how did he die,mr. Addy?
他作为一个战士有点老了 对了,他怎么死的, Addy先生?
Looks like tuberculosis.
看起来像是肺结核
A proud man.
骄傲的男人
It was not the ending he would've wanted.
这一定不是他想要的结局
Yet he was surrounded by family and friends.
而是被亲友簇拥
- A good death. - Oh,please.
- 不错的死法 - 拜托
Now you're describing a scene from lord of the rings.
现在你在讲指环王的情节了
I liked that movie.
我喜欢那部片子
He was buried with respect.
他被尊敬地埋葬
Weapons,jewelry.
武器, 珠宝
His family did not stint or pilfer.
他的家人毫不吝惜
Have you found any spores or fungi,dr. Hodgins?
你找到什么孢子或是真菌了吗? Hodgins博士
Yes.
是的
They correspond both with the time he lived
它们符合他生存的时代
and the geography in which he was found.
和地理环境
What?
怎么了?
I'd like details.
我喜欢细节
- You mean like a written report? - Yes.
- 你是说如同书面报告? - 是的
Our findings will have to bear scholarly scrutiny from our peers.
我们的结论必须能够 经受我们权威学者的考验
What's his problem?
他到底有什么毛病？
my hotel doesn't even have a pool.
我们酒店连游泳池都没有
Well,you're welcome to use mine.
哦, 可以用我的
Well,the breast implant lead went nowhere.
好，这个隆胸找不到什么结果
Well,what about the serial numbers?
那序列号呢?
The implants were reported stolen six months ago.
那块硅胶在六个月前被报失窃
Our victim must've gotten them off the black market.
受害人应当是在黑市上买的
There's a black market in breast implants?
隆胸硅胶也有黑市?
Yeah,we have the name of the doctor from whom the implants were stolen.
有的, 我们找到了被盗硅胶的医生的名字
What use is a black market breast implant?
黑市隆胸硅胶有什么用?
Back-alley plastic surgeons use them.
地下整形外科医生用这些
They're not even real doctors
他们甚至不是合法的医生
Are you gonna write the screenplay?
你打算去写剧本了么？
What screenplay?
什么剧本?
The one based on your book.
根据你的书改编的啊?
Well,I guess,maybe the producer I'm meeting will tell me.
呃, 我想也许我要见的制片商会告诉我
Okay,guys let's turn our attention back to the murder victim.
好了, 伙计们,让我们集中精力 去做这个谋杀案子吧
I'd like to go pay a visit to dr. Boobs.
我想去拜访那位Boobs医生
Why? If implants were stolen from him, he won't know anything.
为什么,如果硅胶是从他那儿偷来的 他什么都不会知道
Because it's the only lead that we've got,finn.
因为这是我们唯一的线索, Finn
And leads are great for screenplays,
而且线索对剧本很重要
or even,say,if you're working a real case.
甚至可以说你是不是在做真实的事
I have something for you.
我有一些东西要给你
Is it chocolate?
巧克力吗?
No.
不是
Then I find my interest has flagged.
那我发现我的兴趣转移了
Nice.
不错
Who is it?
这是谁
It's the hollywood murder victim.
这就是好莱坞谋杀案的受害人
Oh,my god.
呃, 天哪
I see what brennan means.
我懂Brennan的意思了
This woman hasad a lot of surgery.
这个女人进行了许多手术
What's with goodman and hodgins?
Goodman和Hodgins是怎么回事?
They're guys.
男人嘛
They should just lay 'em out on the table and measure.
他们应该公开的较量一下
Lay what out on the table and measure?
把什么公开较量一下?
Okay. Awkward moment.
好了, 够尴尬的了
Let's just say they have different approaches.
我们只能说他们各有各的办事方式
And they're guys,okay?
而且他们是男人, 懂了吗?
I'm a guy.
我也是一个男人
You're more highly evolved.
你是高度进化的男人
This girl didn't just change her face, she changed her skull.
这个女孩不只改变了她的脸 还改变了她的头骨
This is gonna make brennan nuts.
这足以让Brennan发狂
- You know one thing. - What's that?
- 你知道么? - 什么?
She's gonna be beautiful.
她绝对是个美人
Why would anyone go through all this pain and not end up beautiful?
为什么有人承受这么大的痛苦 而不变漂亮的呢？
Do the names michael jackson or joan rivers mean anything to you?
Micheal Jackson或是Joan Rivers 的名字你有印象吗?
One of them.
一个有
The other I'll look up.
另一个我查查看
Every culture nurtures ideals of beauty toward which people strive.
每种文化都教育人们去追求美
Fine,but in the future people will look back
但在未来人们回顾
upon the surgical alterations of the nose or breasts or buttocks with the same horror
整形外科的种种会觉得极端恐怖
that we regard the binding of feet or the use of bronze coils to extend the neck.
正如我们看待裹脚 或是用金属板来扩展脖子一般
You want to speak up?
你很想演讲?
Because it's really hard to hear every word in this very,very quiet waiting room.
这么静的候诊室很难听清你说的每一个词
It's barbaric. It's painful.
这是野蛮和痛苦的
It's wrong.
这是一个天大的错误
This murder victim may never be identified because
这个谋杀案的受害者身份 可能永远得不到确认就是因为
some glorified barber with a medical degree
一些拿着医学学位的美容师
had the arrogance to think that he could do better than millennia of evolution.
狂傲的认为 他可以比千万年来的进化做得更好
Do you know what producer you're meeting with,dr. Brennan?
你知道你要见哪位制片人了吗? Brennan 博士
No,my publisher didn't give me a name.
没有, 我的出版商没有告诉我名字
I don't know what a producer does specifically.
其实我也不知道制片商究竟是干什么的
Nobody does.
没人知道
But it's reay important.
但这的确十分重要
Dr. Kostov will see you now.
Kostov医生现在可以见你了
You can remain here,agent finn.
你可以呆在这儿, Finn 探员
Yes,sir.
是的, 长官
You recognize this,dr. Kostov?
你还记得这个吗, Kostov医生?
That'd be your high-profile double-lumen full "c" saline.
那是高弹性双层硅胶
Yeah,it's from a shipment of implants you reported stolen six months ago.
对, 这就是六个月前你报失的 一批硅胶中的一个
I have a hard time believing you're returning one implant to me.
我真难以置信你居然还一块硅胶给我
I found it in the remains of a murdered girl.
我在一个被谋杀的女孩尸体中发现的
Have any more of those stolen implants been recovered?
还找到了其它的硅胶吗?
Yeah,approximately three weeks ago.
是的, 大约在三个星期以前
There was a faulty one that had to be removed by a surgeon out in the valley.
有一块有缺陷的必须被医生取出
From whom?
从谁那？
- A heidi. - I don't know what that means.
- 一个叫Heidi的 - 我不知道这是什么意思
L.A. Speak for call girl.
洛杉矶称呼应召女郎的
Lapd was investigating. They can tell you what agency the girl was working for.
洛城警局正在调查这个 他们可以告诉你那个女孩是为哪个中介做的
You have the most beautiful bone structure.
你有最完美的骨骼结构
I can't take credit. It's genetic.
我不能接受你的赞扬, 这是天生的
How old are you?
你多大年龄了?
Why do you want to know?
你为什么想知道
Well,it's never too early to watch problem areas.
问题解决得越早越好
The jaw,little pouches beneath the eyes.
下巴, 小眼袋
Do you mind?
你介意吗？
You touch her she'll break your arm.
你碰她的话她会打折你的手
She thinks what you do is...
她觉得你做的是...
barbaric.
野蛮的
Don't look at me. I like my face the way it is.
不要看我, 我喜欢我的自然面目
Sweetie,I'm having a hard time with this skull.
亲爱的, 我在这个头骨上遇到一些麻烦
Did you try filling in the surgical scoring?
你有没有试着考虑一下手术因素
I can't be definitive.
我不能确定
All the usual indicators have been modified.
所有的常规指标都被改过了
I made three variations of facial reconstructions.
我做了三处面部的重建
She had her cheekbones shaved,
她被刮过颧骨
her chin changed, her jaw reconstructed.
她的下巴也改造过了, 还重建了下颌
That's just what she did to her bones.
那仅仅是她对骨骼的改变
We don't have a clue what she did to the soft tissue.
对于她对软组织的改造我们没有任何线索
Her nose,her brows,her cheeks.
她的鼻子, 眉毛, 脸颊
Just start with her basic architecture. We'll go from there.
那就从基本结构入手吧
The basic architecture is what I can't find.
这基本结构正是我找不到的
You're gonna have to make a best estimate.
你应该去做一个最佳的估计
Did you just tell me to guess?
你是告诉我猜吗？
No,I said make a best estimate
不, 我是说做最好的估计
based upon your experience and expertise.
基于你的经验和专长
Okay,well,dress it up however you want,
但是, 不管怎么弄
but it's still a guess.
还是猜测啊
Look,my experience and my expertise don't extend to this.
看,我的经验和专长并不能用来猜
A facial reconstruction might not be helpful in this case.
脸部重建也许在这次并没有用
Angela,I told you it'd be hard.
Angela, 我告诉过你这个很难
Just do what you can.
尽你所能嘛
Okay,brenn,you're being a little edgy and tart with me.
呃, Brenn你对我有一点焦躁了
And all I'm trying to do is tell you the truth.
而且我努力要做的就是告诉你真相
What this young woman did to herself--
这个年轻女人对自己的所作所为 --
it's as if she completely removed her own identity.
就好像她完全消去了自己的特征
Who hates herself so much that she not only changes her looks,
有谁会像她那么恨自己以至于 不仅改变自己的外貌
but her core architecture?
还改变了自己的结构
If we don't know who she is
如果我们连她是谁都不知道
then how will we be able to catch the person who murdered her?
那我们怎么能够抓住那个谋杀她的罪犯呢?
Is that your way of apologizing?
这是你的道歉?
Yes,angela.
是的, Angela
I accept.
我接受
I love your guts,sweetie.
我喜欢你的坚持, 亲爱的
According to lapd,a black market breast implant
根据洛城警局, 同一批货的硅胶
from the same shipment showed up in another girl from aphrodite escorts.
到了另一个来自Aphrodite Escorts 的姑娘体内
Are you missing anyone?
有什么人失踪了么?
We're not looking into your business,ms. Bardu.
我们并没有干涉你的业务, Bardu小姐
We're just trying to solve a murder.
我们只是在调查一起谋杀
I haven't heard from rachel in two weeks.
我已经两个礼拜没有Racheal的消息了
Is that unusual?
那不正常吗?
I prefer to ask the questions my own way,agent finn.
我喜欢用自己的方式提问, Finn探员
Thanks.
谢谢
Rachel booked out at a one-week rate.
Rachel一般一星期登记一次外出
She knows to check in with me if the client wants to extend the contract.
如果有客户希望延长合同 她知道要我核对一下
It's time to worry.
是时候开始担心了
Do any of these women resemble rachel?
这里面有人长得像Rachel吗?
If I had to pick one,this is the closest,but not really.
如果我必须要挑一个,这是最接近的 但并不完全
Rachel have a last name?
Rachel姓什么?
Rachel wasn't even her real first name.
Rachel甚至不是她的真名
She goes by rachel lachance.
是按Rachel Lachance来起的
Rachel went to vegas with a long-time customer.
Rachel和一个长期客户去拉斯维加斯了
I need his name.
我需要他的名字
Ms. Bardu,it's always the same story--
Bardu小姐, 故事都差不多
a beautiful young woman.
一个美丽的年轻女人
Somebody wants to meet her.
有人想见她
Somebody can't have her. Somebody dies.
有人不能得到她, 有人就死了
Dr. Anton kostov. An assembly-line nip/tucker in town.
Anton kostov 医生，这个城里的整形医生
If that's all...
如果完了的话...
do you have a card, ms. Bardu?
你有名片吗, Bardu小姐?
We provide a law enforcement discount.
我们给执法人员打折
Ms. Bardu,do you have any idea what rachel looked like before her plastic surgery?
Bardu小姐, 你对Rachel整容前的长相有印象吗?
Which time?
什么时候？
The skull is in extremely good shape.
这个头骨保存的非常好
Cranial measurements are congruent with ancient saxons,celts and pre-aryans.
头盖骨的测量符合撒克逊人 凯尔特人和史前雅利安人
Which matches the location of the find.
与发现地相符
I used saxon tissue depth for the markers.
我用撒克逊人的组织做标记
However,every skull requires its own unique demands.
然后, 每一个头骨有它独特的需求
Are you certain of your calculations,ms. Montenegro?
你确信你的计算, Montenegro小姐?
A lot more certain than I am on brennan's hollywood hooker case.
比我对Brennan的好莱坞案件确信多了
This is a pict.
这是皮克特人
Picti actually means "painted ones" in latin.
拉丁文中表示"纹身的人"
The romans feared them.
罗马人害怕他们
Very little was written about them or by them.
很少有他们的记录
Fierce warriors,falsely reported to be small in stature.
勇猛的战士, 不实地被描绘成小个子
He's a pict. So what?
他是个皮克特人, 那有如何？
The picts are from the far,far north of the british isles,
皮克特人来自于遥远的不列颠群岛
far above hadrian's wall.
大概在离Hadrian墙很远的地方
The remains were found at an archaeological site  in southern england,near wales.
其它的在南英格兰威尔士 附近的考古遗址中被发现
A pict can't go for a walk?
皮克特人不能迁徙么？
These remains represent an archaeological anomaly.
这些遗址显示出了考古学上的一些异常
This is unique in that no pict has ever been found in this area before.
是因为皮克特人 从来没有在这个地区被发现过
If we can remove the clothing and take a closer look at the bones...
如果我们可以把衣服除去 再靠近仔细看看这些骨骼
it's a face.
这是一张脸
- Maybe angela got it wrong. - Hey!
- 也许Angela搞错了 - 嘿!
- Or zack screwed up the measurements. - Hey!
- 或Zack 把测量搞砸了 - 嘿
This whole pict business sounds like one of your stories.
这整个皮克特人的故事 听起来像你的某个故事
enough
够了
Are you trying to get fired?
你想被炒吗?
Science is no country for storytellers,baby.
科学不是小说家的乐园, 伙计
Kostov knew rachel as a patient and as a client.
Kostov知道Rachel是个病人 而且她知道他是个客户
Kostov wasn't the victim's only plastic surgeon.
Kostov并不是受害者惟一的整形外科医生
These are ten-times magnifications of the victim's jawbone surgery.
这是放大了十倍的受害人下颚外科手术图
Kostov doesn't do work this sophisticated.
Kostov不会做得这么精细
Meaning she had more than one plastic surgeon.
表明她还有其它的整形外科医生
Zack addy.
Zack Addy
I live to serve.
我为服务而生
Zack,this facial surgery--
Zack, 这个面部手术--
the edges of the bone are almost scalloped,
骨头的边缘的刀口有圆齿
as if the blade simultaneously cut and applied torsion.
好像刀片在同时切削和旋转
You need to know if this procedure is recognized
你需要去了解这个手术程序
and sanctioned by the american medical association.
是否经过了美国联合医学会的批准
You think kostov is performing illegal surgical procedures?
你认为Kostov是做了非法的外科手术?
It won't help us to discover the identity of our victim,
这对我们鉴定受害人的身份并没有帮助
but it might help us catch her killer.
但也许有助于我们抓住凶手
That's the point,bones.
这才是重点, Bones
- What? - To catch the murderer.
- 什么? - 抓住凶手?
I'm sending you a catalogue of all the stuff they sent me.
我正在发给你一份 他们给我的所有材料的目录
Soil samples,pollen,particulates,etc., That were on the body parts.
土壤采样, 花粉, 微粒等, 采自尸体上的
Nothing too surprising except for e-glass fibers.
没有什么让人吃惊的东西, 除了玻璃光纤
She didn't pick that up in a field.
她不会是在旷野中捡的
No,it's marine fiberglass.
不, 那是航海光纤
The victim was on a boat shortly before she died.
受害人死前曾在一艘船上
Also,look at this.
另外, 看看这个
A fingernail-- probably her own.
一块手指甲--恐怕是她自己的
I sent it to the fbi crime lab so they could run dna tests.
我把这个送到FBI罪案实验室 以便他们进行DNA测试
That's zirconium,by the way,not a diamond,
顺便说一句, 那是锆, 不是钻石
so I'm guessing she wasn't your top-drawer,high-class prostitute.
所以我猜测她不是高级应召女郎
All the osteological perturbations are consistent with recent elective surgeries,
所有骨骼上的混乱都和最近的外科手术有关
except for compound fractures in the right tibia and fibula,
除了右胫骨和腓骨上的骨折痕迹
which indicate traumatic compression ante-adrenarche.
很明显是压缩性外伤
The victim had her leg crushed.
受害人的腿被压碎过
Probably in a car accident around age 13...
可能在大概13岁时有过一次车祸
excuse me,that's my cell phone!
对不起, 那是我的电话
I analyzed the molars.
我分析了臼齿
Oxygen and strontium isotopes in the enamel indicate early childhood in new england,
牙齿瓷釉中的锶同位素和氧测定 表明她的童年是在新英格兰度过的
while the dentin suggests six to ten years in southern california.
然而牙质显示六到十岁时她生活在南加州
Hey,ms. Bardu,hi. Special agent booth. I reconsidered your offer.
嘿, Bardu小姐, 嗨，booth 特工 我重新考虑了你的提议
I was wondering if I could have one of your ladies visit me today.
我在想能否叫你的一个小姐今天来我这里
You're ordering a prostitute from my cell phone?
你用我的手机召妓?
I was wondering if rachel ever took part in any of those two-on-one specials.
我想知道Rachel是否参加过任何 二对一的特别服务
Hey,the old two-on-one special-- classic.
嘿, 二对一特别服务? --经典
- What's a classic? - That's great.
- 什么经典？ - 太好了
Just send me whoever she worked wi the most.
给我送个常做这个的过来嘛
You're ordering a hooker to my hotel?
你召了妓来我的酒店?
Did I hear you say hooker?
是说妓女吗?
How come I never get to go on these out-of-town trips?
我怎么从来没有外地出差的机会
'Cause you have much looser daily allowances than I do.
因为你比我有更多的日常补贴
Well,have fun.
好啦, 开好玩
- I have to get up early tomorrow. - Why?
- 我明天必须要早起 - 为什么
I'm meeting the producer.
我要去见制片商
Oh,you're one of those guys.
哦, 你是那些家伙中的一个
What guys?
哪些家伙？
One of those guys who say they just want to talk.
那些说只想和我谈谈的家伙中的一个
I do just want to talk.
我真的只是想谈谈
I'm an fbi agent.
我是一个FBI探员
Okay,I get the drill.
好吧, 我接受过这种训练
What am I playing?
我要扮演什么?
No,really,leslie,I...
不, 说真的, Leslie, 我...
I really am an fbi agent.
我真是一个FBI探员
I just want to ask you some questions,that's all.
我只是想问你一些问题, 就这些
- About what? - About your friend rachel.
- 关于什么 - 关于你的朋友Rachel
Look,I'm sorry,but I think...
对不起, 但我认为
I think she's been murdered.
我认为她已经被杀了
This can't be happening
这不可能
Oh,god.
噢, 天哪
Rachel was so nice.
Rachel是如此出色
She was really an actress.
她是个真正的演员
You know,the way  i'm really a singer.
你知道, 就象说我是一个歌手
We all say we're something different than what we are.
我们一直说 我们其实与现在的自己有点不同
None of us want to be what we are.
没有谁愿意成为现在这个样子
You know rachel's real name?
你知道Rachel的真名吗?
Candice.
Candice
Candice hayden.
Candice Hayden
But I doubt that was her real name.
但我怀疑那是不是她的真名
She said she was from stockton,but I told her I was from coeur d'alene,
她说她来自Stockton 我告诉她我来自 Coeur d'alene
and I was lying,so...
但我撒谎了, 所以...
do you know why anyone would want candice dead?
你知不知道有人想Candice死?
We see things we shouldn't all the time.
我们总是看到一些不该看到的东西
We know things about powerful people they don't want us to know.
我们知道一些权力人物 不想让我们知道的事
Candice have anyone in her life?
Candice有碰到这种人吗?
Nick.
Nick
For a while.
有一段时间
I forget his last name,but he played some kind of terrorist on 24.
我忘记他姓什么了 但他扮演的是反恐24中的恐怖分子的角色
He got killed in like four seconds.
他在几乎四秒钟内被杀死
Nick know that candice was a call girl?
Nick知不知道Candice是应召女郎?
No.Not at first
不, 起先不知道
And when he found out he was really mad.
当他发现的时候就很生气
He smashed out all the windows of her car.
他砸碎了她的所有车窗
I'm sorry,miss,but you're gonna have to leave.
对不起, 小姐, 但你必须要走了
Listen,buddy, I don't know what your problem is,
听着, 伙计, 我不知道你有什么问题
but this is my little sister,okay?  I'm visiting from c'oeur d'alene,
但这是我的妹妹,明白吗? 我从 c'oeur d'alene 专程来看她
and I asked her here for a drink which is taking a hell of a long time,by the way.
我请她到这儿来喝一杯, 顺便说一句 会用不少时间
I'm sorry,sir,but we have strict rules...
对不起, 先生, 但我们有严格的规定...
you might want to have a little respect.
你应该学会尊重
And check on those drinks for us,okay,pal?
去看一下我们要喝的东西, 好吗?
- Yes,sir. - Thank you.
- 是 - 谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢
So...
那么...
we're just gonna sit here and have a drink?
我们仅仅只是坐在这里喝点酒吗?
That's all?
就这样?
That's all,leslie.
就这样, Leslie
Have a drink,
喝一点
enjoy the view and,
享受风景
hopefully,catch us a killer.
希望可以抓住凶手
agent booth, can I have a moment,please?
Booth 探员, 打扰一下好吗?
have I done something to offend you?
我是否做了一些冒犯你的事?
Look,I'm not really into thiswhole west coast
瞧, 我不是到西海岸来
in touch with your feelings thing,okay? So...
和你作感情交流的,好吗? 所以...
yeah. Um...
是的，嗯...
I'm really good at my job
我真的很擅长我的工作
and I've been nothing but cooperative and helpful to you,
而且我没有其它意思 仅仅是想和你合作  帮助你
but you just freeze me out.
但你却把我晾在一边
Mm-hmm.
嗯...
And I know you have nothing against working with women
而且我知道你对和女性工作没有偏见
because you're partners with dr. Brennan,so...
因为你和Brennan博士是拍档, 所以...
your problem must be with me.
所以你的问题肯定是和我有关
Look,I don't have anything against you,agent finn.
我没有什么针对你的, Finn 探员
I just don't like the way you view the fbi.
我只是不喜欢你对FBI的观点
What do you mean?
什么意思?
This is a proud and noble job,
这是一个自豪而高尚的工作
but you're using it to get to something else.
但你用来达到其它目标
My advice:
我的建议是:
Write you script,get an agent--
写你的脚本, 找一个探员--
hell,have a little plastic surgery--
然后, 再进行一个小的整容手术--
but quit using my federal bureau of investigation
只是不要再用FBI的身份
as a stepping-stone into something that you think is better.
来作你认为更好的东西的垫脚石
Because in my book,
因为在我的字典里
there is nothing better.
没有其它什么事更好的了
I'm here with penny marshall,
我在这里和Penny Marshall 一起
one of the most prolific hyphenates in hollywood,
好莱坞最高产的人之一
actress,producer and director of such hits as a league of their own and big.
演员, 制片商和导演
Her latest project is bred in the bone.
她最新的计划是"深入骨骼"
It's a thriller based on the novel  by crime-
一部根据和犯罪斗争的人类学者 Temperance Brennan博士
fighting anthropologist dr. Temperance brennan.
的小说改编而成的电影
Okay. So,how did this all come together?
那么所有这些是怎么集中到一块的呢?
I have no idea.
我不知道
Well,my brother gary gave me the book and I liked it,
我兄弟Gary给了我这本书而且我喜欢它
and then this whole bidding war started,
然后这个出价大战就开始了
and I don't usually get into that kind of thing, but in this case...
我一般不喜欢介入这种事，但这一次...
a bidding war?
出价大战?
That's got to be a thrill for a first-time author.
对于新手作家来说真是恭维了
I wasn't actually there.
我其实并不知情
You must be a big fan of penny's films.
你一定是Penny的电影的大影迷
So,which one's your favorite?
那么, 哪一部是你最喜欢的?
Well,I enjoyed her humorous treatment of the time-space paradox.
恩, 我喜欢她在处理时空矛盾时的幽默
Big!
大的!
Yeah. Very funny.
很有意思
Time-space paradox.
时空矛盾
Penny,who is going to write the script?
Penny, 谁来写这个脚本?
Don'T...
不要...
I get to do that?
不是说我来做吗？
We'll talk.
我们会谈到的
cut. Stop.
卡, 停下
Whatever you say.
不管你说什么
Brennan.
Brennan
Well,I want to come with you.
我要和你一起去
I have to go 'cause we have a suspect and... I have to go.
我必须走了, 因为找到了一个嫌疑人... 我必须走
Would you look at that passion.
你看那激情
Pretty good chance that one of these leaping loses is our killer.
那群跳跃的人中的某个 很有可能就是我们要找的凶手
You always think it's a boyfriend.
你总觉得是她的男朋友
Well,he loved her,found out that she was a prostitute.
恩, 他爱她, 发现她原来是个妓女
I'd say anyone who plays this stupid game is capable of murder.
我说任何一个玩这种愚蠢的游戏的 都可能是凶手
Well,then,you got this case sewed up,\
那么, 你要结案了
why don't you just go and arrest them all?
为什么不直接过去然后逮捕他们所有人?
Excuse me,guys.
打扰了, 先生们
Ladies.
女士们
Ladies,gentlemen. Excuse me. Please.
女士们, 先生们, 打扰了, 对不起
Hey,everyone who isn't nick harbison go get the ball.
嘿, 所有不是Nick Harbison的人去捡球
God,she was so sweet.
天哪, 她真的很好
I actually thought about getting back together with her, even though...
我真的考虑过回去和她一起, 哪怕...
... you broke all the windows in her car?
...你打碎了她车窗的所有玻璃?
Well,what would you do if you found out your girlfriend was a prostitute?
如果是你发现你的女友是妓女 你会怎么做?
When did you last see rachel?
你最后一次看到Rachel是什么时候?
Sandra.
Sandra
Her name was sandra kane,at least as far as I knew.
她叫Sandra Kane, 至少我知道的是这样
When did you last see sandra?
那你最后一次看到Sandra是什么时候?
About a month ago.
大概一个月以前
I was tending bar at a function at the colony.
我在聚居区照看一家酒吧
Did you speak to her?
你和她讲话了吗?
No.
没有
No,I was working.
没有, 我在工作
So was he.
她也是
I didn't kill her.
我并没有杀她
How could you not know what she was doing for money?
你怎么可能不知道她是怎么赚钱的?
Did you even know her at all?
你了解她吗?
She said she was modeling. The thing about sandra is that,
她说她是模特, 关于Sandra
and as pretty as she was,
她很漂亮
she was just never pretty enough.
只是永远漂亮得不够
She'd be all black and blue,
她遍体鳞伤
and then she would heal and she would look beautiful.
然后去医治, 看起来就很漂亮
I mean really,really beautiful,
我是说真的真的漂亮
and we'd be sure that something was gonna break for her,
让人心碎的美
and,of course,itouldn'T.
但, 不可能
And then she would be back in front of that mirror,
她又重新坐回镜子面前
and no matter what I said...
并且无论我说什么...
look,look.
看吧
I-I never knew her, I never understood her.
我-我根本不了解她 我从来都不理解她
I'm probably the last guy you should be asking about her.
我恐怕是你问关于 她的问题的最后一人了
He's an actor. Of course he's convincing.
他是个演员, 当然会令人相信
I don't know. Doesn't seem to work very much.
我不知道, 但看起来他并不常工作
He's playing volleyball in the middle of the day.
他在大中午的玩排球
Just an observation.
只是一个观察
I have an announcement.
我要宣布一件事
You are unable to positively authenticate the skeleton.
你不能肯定地鉴定这个骨骼
That is correct.
正确
Told you.
告诉过你了
Given the inconsistencies between the specimen's geographic location,
由于样本的地理位置与地势
physiognomy and artifacts,
以及史前古器物之间存在的矛盾
I cannot in good faith authenticate the find.
我无法准确鉴定我们的发现
Is this because of how I made him look?
是因为我弄的长相?
'Cause there's a certain amount of subjectivity involved in recreating a face.
因为在重建面部的过程中 融入了太多的主观因素?
A certain amount,yes,but,
是有一些, 但是
the fact is,he displays pictish features.
关键在于, 他表现出了皮克特族的特性
For all we know,this skull doesn't belong to this body.
据我们所知 这个头骨并不属于这个身体
Even though on x-rays it looks as though
尽管在X光线下看起来是这样
the head is properly attached to the spinal cord,
头可能是附在脊髓骨上的
we could actually go in and look, confirm the authenticity.
我们确实应该看看, 确认其真实性
I decline to continue the investigation at this time.
我拒绝现在继续进行这项研究
We will store the remains in the interim.
我们应该把遗骸暂时保存
I knew this was gonna happen.
我就知道是这样
Hodgins...
because we have been colleagues on this,
因为在这次事情上我们是同事的关系
more than superior and subordinate,
而不是上下级的关系
iave allowed you to be insubordinate, but I warn you,dr. Hodgins,
我允许你不服从命令, 但我要警告你 Hodgins博士
that is over.
一切已经结束了
Do you want my letter of resignation?
你想要我写辞职信么?
You know what would be better?
你知道要怎么好起来
Put them on the table and measure. Right?
把事情摊开来衡量一下, 对吧?
Okay,look,everybody just turn and walk away.
好了，大家都转身离开吧
If you want me to resign,
如果你要我辞职
just say so.
告诉我就好
Ms. Montenegro is right.
Montenegro小姐是对的
You think you just won something.
你认为你刚才获胜了么?
I'm telling you, goodman was the bigger man.
我告诉你, Goodman才是赢家
Isn't it against your ethical code to have sexual relations with a patient,
是因为与病人有性关系 就违背了伦理法则么?
or do you guys even have an ethical code?
还是你们还有伦理法则?
Sex with patients is frowned upon.
与病人有性关系不是件好事
That's why he said the implants were stolen.
那就是他为什么说硅胶被偷了
No way to prove that he was the one who installed them.
就没有办法来证明是他装的了
I did not know rachel was dead when you last visited,
你上一次来的时候 我根本不知道Rachel已经死了
and I did not kill rachel.
并且我也没有杀Rachel
I made her beautiful.
我让她变得漂亮
You mean you took what was unique and particular about her and destroyed it.
你是说你找到了她的特征并且消毁了它
You have a serious neurosis on the subject.
你在这个问题上太神经质了
Do you have a boat?
你有船吗?
I do four boob jobs a day, 20 grand a pop.
我一天做四个蠢蛋的工作
Of course I have a boat.
当然有艘船
That's all you get without a lawyer.
那是你在没有律师时能知道的全部了
So what do you do,huh? Pay him in hair plugs?
你要怎么做, 嗯? 给他一点毛发附件吗?
Still working on the murder weapon?
还在找罪案凶器吗?
If it's not a knife,maybe it's some kind of sharpened screwdriver.
如果那不是一把刀 也许是一种锋利的螺丝起子
Why are you being so mean to dr. Goodman?
你为什么要那样对Goodman 博士?
I'm not being mean. I'm being critical of his process.
我没有怎样对他, 我只是不满意他的程序
Why are you being so critical of his process?
你为什么质疑他的程序呢?
Goodman should be looking at the facts.
Goodman应该去查找真相
Is this skeleton authentic or not? That's all.
究竟这个骨架可信不可信, 就这样
Instead,it's all a mishmash of conjecture.
而不是把猜测混作一谈
What I think is he's forgotten how to do the science and doesn't want to admit it.
我认为他已经忘记了怎样做科学研究 而且并不愿意承认这一点
Why a screwdriver?
为什么是一把螺丝起子呢?
Because there's more torsion in the cut
因为在伤口
than a flat-bladed knife could bear without snapping.
有比平叶片能承受的更多的扭曲
It twists without breaking.
它旋转而且没有折断
The killer would have to be incredibly strong,
凶手应该是难以置信的强壮
and even then,the blade would snap.
而且即使这样, 刀片也会断
That's what brennan said about the jaw surgery thing.
那就是Brennan说的下颚外科手术
- What? - I don't know.
- 什么? - 我不知道
I do bugs and silt, but she said the words "torsion" and "twist" and "cut."
我只是做了虫子和泥沙, 但她说过"扭转" "弯曲" 和 "切削" 这几个词
This is the type of situation where people say,"oh,my god."
这就是人们会说 "噢, 上帝"的那种情形
Pretend you're a person and say it.
假装你是那个人再说一次
Oh,my god.
噢, 上帝
Scenario number one:
假设一:
Prostitute gets breast augmentation from plastic surgeon in return for sex.
妓女想通过隆胸手术来作为性的报答
- She threatens to tell on him. - Plausible.
- 她威胁要去告他 - 有可能是这样
Scenario number two. Jealous boyfriend. Well,yada yada.
假设二: 猜疑的男友，哦, 哈哈
You know the rest.
你知道结果的
- Which do you like? - Neither.
- 你喜欢哪一个? - 都不
Because there's no real evidence.
因为没有证据
Unless you count a volleyball.
除非你指望排球
It sounds like you're getting ready to quit.
听起来好像你打算放弃
Quit? No.
放弃? 不
The deputy director wants me to hand the case over to L.A. Field office.
办事处主任要我移交这个案子给 洛杉矶地方办公室
Wee supposed to give agent finn what we got and... go home.
我们应该给Finn探员我们所有的资料... 然后回家
What? Forget it.
什么? 算了吧
You don't even like agent finn. You think she's an idiot.
你都不喜欢Finn 探员 你觉得她是一个白痴
Bones,the whole case is a bust,it's a blank.
Bones, 整个案子就是一个谜, 一片空白
We-we don't have anything. We checked her apartment. Nothing.
我们-我们没有任何东西 我们检查了她的公寓, 一无所获
There are no pictures,nothing.
连张照片都没有
We don't know what she looks like. We don't know her name...
我们不知道她长什么样 不知道她叫什么名字...
it's like she lived onthe world instead of in it.
看起来她好像活着但并不实际存在
Cullen is calling you back because he thinks i'm at a dead end. You...
Cullen打电话叫你回去因为 他觉得我已经没有办法了, 你...
you have to tell him he's wrong.
你应该告诉他他错了
Is he wrong?
他错了吗?
We know we're looking for someone who grew up in new england,
我们知道 我们在找一个在新英格兰长大的
moved here about eight years ago.
大约在八年前搬来这儿
Her leg was crushed in a car accident when she was 13.
13岁时曾因车祸压断过腿
She was on a boat shortly before she was murdered.
在被杀前在船上呆过一段时间
We know some of her names and some of her faces.
我们知道她的一些名字和情况
That's all your stuff.
那都是你的资料
Usually,by now, we know more about my stuff.
通常情况下, 到这一步 我应该找到更多的资料
We have separate stuff?
我们的资料是分开的吗?
Yeah. By now,I usually have a feel for the person.
是的, 通常到现在为止 我对这个人有一定的感觉
What they wanted, how they felt...
她们想要什么, 她们的感觉...
what was going on in their lives-- with this girl,nothing.
她们生活中发生的事-- 关于这女孩,却什么也没有
She thought she was ugly.
她认为自己长得丑
She did everything she could to make herself beautiful,
她用尽一切办法让自己漂亮
and all she did was make herself more invisible.
她做的一切让她更加难以找到
Everybody in this citythinks they're ugly,
城市中的每个人都觉得自己丑
and nobody is.
其实根本不是
I'm starting to get why you have anonymous death so much.
我开始了解你为什么厌恶无名氏的死亡
We're born unique.
我们的出生是惟一的
Our experiences mold and change us.
我们的经历塑造并改变了我们
We become someone,all of us, and to have that taken away by murder,
我们成了某个人, 我们所有人 然后有人被谋杀
to be erased from existence against our will,it's just...
违背我们自己的意愿把我们从世界上消除 仅仅是...
- evil? - Unacceptable.
- 邪恶? - 不可接受
These bones you bring me--
你给我带来的这些骨头 --
I give them a face, I say their names out loud,
我给她们做了脸, 大声喊她们的名字
I return them to their loved ones,and you arrest the bad guy.
我恢复她们生前的样子 然后你去把坏人逮捕
I like that.
我喜欢这样
So do I.
我也是
I feel like we should be arresting these...
我觉得我们应该逮捕这些...
doctors, because whether they killed her or not, they...
医生, 因为无论他们是否杀了她,他们...
they still erased her.
他们还把她的特征给消除了
Well,maybe I could hold cullen off for a day.
好啊, 也许我可以一天抓一个
That's not good enough.
那样还不够
You're welcome.
不客气
brennan.
Brennan
The murder weapon is a larger version of the surgical implement
杀人凶器是一把大型的外科手术器械
used on the victim's jaw.
用于受害人的下颚
You compared the wounds to the marks left on her jaw?
你比对了这个伤口和她下颚上的痕迹?
That's brilliant,zack.
聪明, Zack
It was hodgins-- well, hodgins quoting you,so...
那是Hodgins -- 哦, Hodgins引用了你的话, 那么
it was us. Go team.
就是我们的，都是一队
But get this.
但是
According to the national plastic surgery association,
根据国家整形外科手术联合会的资料
there's only one surgeon who does this procedure.
只有一个外科医生在做这个手术
Tell me he's in L.A.
告诉我他在洛杉矶
He's in L.A.
他的确在洛杉矶
Okay,dr. Henry atlas rodeo drive,beverly hills.
好，Henry Atlas 医生 Rodeo Drive, Beverly 山冈
Go.
走
Hically bound to ask you for a warrant before
按理我应该问你们要许可证
revealing the identity of any of my patients.
在你们想获得我任何病人的资料之前
Let me try this then.
我试试
The job procedure which dr. Brennan described to you...
Brennan博士描述给你的工作程序
was my innovation,yes.
是我的改革创新, 是的
There's an adage in my business:
在我的工作中有一句格言:
"You can't alter the bone."
"你不能改变骨骼"
I've proven itincorrect,
我终于证明了这是错误的
given the right patients.
只要有合适的病人
How many have you done?
你做了多少例病人?
Perhaps half a dozen.
大概有六个
And if you get a warrant,
如果你有授权
I will release the names of my patients; otherwise...
我会告诉你我病人的名单，否则...
do you use special operating instruments?
你是不是用特别的手术器械
Yes; I designed them myself, specially for the procedure.
是的, 我自己设计的, 专门是为这种手术
Have you patented them,or shared the design with anyone?
你是否为他们申请过专利 或是与其它人分享过这个设计
Not yet.
还没有
He's waiting till he has enough success stories to cash in.
他在等待足够的成功案例来证明有效
He's going to be short one success story.
他还少了一个成功案例
That's right. Let's see what we got here:
对, 我们看看我们能找到些什么
Sandra kane?
Sandra Kane?
Rachel lachance? Candice haden?
Rachel Lachance? Candice Haden?
Any of these women-- they ring a bell?
这些女人 -- 她们都是应召?
As I have reiterated...
我已经反复说过了...
I have a search warrant here...
我有搜查证...
to collect your surgical instruments.
来收集你的手术器械
You'll... you'll shut me down.
你会... 你会使我关门的
You will cost me a fortune.
你会让我损失一大笔钱
The only ones we require,dr. Atlas, are the ones you've designed yourself.
我们惟一需要的, Atlas 医生 是你自己设计的那个
She told me her name was susan shepherd.
她告诉我她叫Susan Shepherd
brilliant.
聪明
you wanted to see me?
你想见我?
You are a very difficult and stubborn man,dr. Hodgins.
你真是个顽固的难处的人, Hodgins博士
Right now,I'd like nothing more than to fire you.
现在, 我最好解雇你
In my position,very few people...
在我的位置上, 很少有人...
tell me the truth anymore.
告诉我真相
I find I enjoy it...
我发现我很享受...
in some... perverse way.
在一些... 非正常途径
You willing to admit you bailed on the authentication?
你愿意承认你在鉴定方面的错误了?
Yes.
是的
Seriously?
认真的?
But not for the reasons you think.
但不是因为你想的那个原因
True,
好吧
we might be able toauthenticate the skeleton by taking him apart,
我们可以鉴别这具骨架 通过把他分开
destroying him.
摧毁他
If he's a fake,that would be fine,nothing lost. But I think...
如果他是赝品, 那很好, 没什么损失 但我认为...
he's the real thing.
他是真的
You do know he's been dead for 1,500 years,right?
你确实知道他已经死了1500年了, 对吗?
I am an archaeologist.
我是一个考古学家
This is what we do.
这是我们做的事
We step outside the facts and tell ourselves the story of an individual or a culture.
我们揭开真相 告诉我们自己一个人或一个文明的故事
And if the story I tell myself about this man
如果我告诉自己的关于这个生活在
who lived 1,500 years ago is true,
1500年前的人的故事是真的
if he was laid to rest by people who respect and loved him...
如果他要被放在那里受万人尊崇和爱戴...
don't I owe it to them not to let the pure scientist desecreate his remains?
难道我不应该让他免遭纯科学家的损坏
Or...
或者...
you could be totally rational and say
你可以理性的告诉我
you were waiting for imaging technology to improve to the point
你在等待成像技术进步
where it wasn't necessary
到不必
to disassemble him.
肢解他
Ah...
啊...
yes.
是的
I suppose I could say that; it's less,uh...
我想我可以那样说
sentimental.
少点感伤
For the pure scientists.
为这些纯科学家
I've got the murder weapon.
我找到凶器了
We have the murder weapon.
我们找到凶器了
We have trace evidence from your boat.
我们在你的船上找到了痕迹
We have testimony from your staff that you argued with a woman
我们从你的职员那里得知
you knew as susan shepherd,shortly before she died.
你曾经和名叫Susan Shepherd的有过争执 就在她死前不久
So what you need now is a confession.
所以你现在需要做的就是招供
Your patient list is what's known as,uh,
你的病员列表是, 据我所知, 呃
"a-list," right?
"高级人物 - 列表" 对吗?
Oscar winners,
奥斯卡获得者
supermodels, super-agents...
超级名模, 超级明星...
moguls.
显赫人物
So how is it that a call girl makes the grade?
一个妓女怎么可以上升到这个级别?
You can answer that,henry.
你可以回答这个问题, Henry
I did susan's procedure pro bono.
我是在帮Bono做手术前给Susan做的
Why?
为什么?
Because she volunteered.
因为她志愿的
she was a guinea pig.
她只是实验品
How'd you meet her?
你怎么认识她的?
Aw,come on.
噢, 拜托
Susan didn't just walk into your office,did she?
Susan不可能只是走进你的办公室, 是吧?
Oh,just tell them,henry.
哦, 告诉他们吧, Benry
Through another call girl-- one I used regularly.
是通过另一个应召女郎--一个我经常找的
Sometimes,these girls from the high-class
有时候, 这些从一流公司出来的女孩
establishments start to have expectations beyond the professional.
在成为专业的之前都有很高的期望值
She thought you were gonna marry her?
她认为你会娶她?
Something along those lines,yes.
从某种程度上讲是这样
So I made a change. I started requesting susan.
所以我换人了, 我开始邀请Susan
Did you trade plastic surgery for sexual favors?
你做整形手术是为了性爱好?
Obfuscate,henry.
这是迷惑你的, Henry
We did each other favors.
我们各有所得
Went fine for a few months.
我们友好相处了几个月
Until susan wanted you to marry her,too.
直到Susan也要求你娶她
No. In my opinion,susan had become addicted to plastic surgery.
不, 在我看来, Susan开始变得 沉溺于整形外科手术
I refused to do any more procedures.
我拒绝再帮她做其他手术
That's what my staff heard us arguing about.
那就是我的属下听到我们争吵的原因
What was susan like?
Susan是一个什么样的女孩?
she was the girl nt door.
邻家女孩样的
Simple,healthy...
单纯, 健康...
the girl before susan was the opposite. She was very flashy.
Susan之前的女孩正好相反, 很浮华
She had diamonds in her incisors,diamonds in her fingernails.
她在门牙和指甲上都镶了钻石
Bones,didn't hodgins find a fingernail?
Bones, Hodgins找到了一片指甲对吧?
Yes,with a fake diamond in it.
是的, 上面有一块假钻石
But susan was the girl-next-door type.
但Susan是邻家女孩那型
It wasn't her fingernail.
那不是她的指甲
Jealousy. Like I said.
嫉妒, 就正如我说过的那样
So,what was the name of the escort before susan?
Susan之前的那个女孩叫什么?
The flashy one,the one who thought you were gonna marry her?
浮华的那个, 就那个认为你要娶她的？
Tell the man what he needs to know,henry.
告诉他所有他想知道的, Henry
she thought atlas was gonna take her out of the life.
她觉得Atlas会把她的生活带走
He wanted the girl next door.
他想要邻家女孩
You were right:
你是对的
Jealousy.
嫉妒
Ah,it's an old story.
呵, 这是一个古老的故事了
Bet your 1,500-year-old friend back home heard a version.
你1500岁的朋友回来的话都听过
When she thought rachel was stealing her man
她觉得Rachel抢走了她的男人
She killed her
便杀了她
What did she ask you?
她问了你什么?
What?
什么?
She asked you something after she was arrested-- what was it?
她在被捕以后问了你一些事 问了些什么?
She asked me...
她问我...
if I thought she was beautiful.
我是否觉得她漂亮
I got one more thing: I had the bureau search for adolescent girls
还有一件事, 我让局里面查找了这个女孩
that were injured in car crashes in the upper northeast,
就是曾经在十到十二年前
ten to 12 years ago.
在北部遭遇过车祸的
Daughter's right leg was crushed.
女孩的右腿被撞了
Alison...
her name was alison holmes.
她叫Alison Holmes
Her father and her brother are still alive
她的父亲和兄弟都还活着
somewhere in bangor,maine.
Bangor Maine的某处
We'll return the remains.
我们会交还遗体
Thanks,booth.
多谢了, Booth
Well,bones...
好的, Bones...
you do your thing,
你做你最拿手的
I do mine.
我做我的
Look at her.
看看她
Yeah;
是啊
pretty little thing.
可爱的小东西
-------------------------- www.ydy.com/bbs Proudly Presents --------------------------
-------------------------- 本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用 禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负 --------------------------
Sync: YTET-Starry -==www.ydy.com/bbs==-
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: Marcella Macready 校对: Sybil 时间轴: YYET-Starry
BONES Season 1 Episode 10
识骨追踪 第一季第十集